(晴明)思い出せ！
お前が惚れた女は➡
Remember!
Was the woman you loved meant to
stand in the rain under a dark sky?
暗き空の下で
雨に濡れる女であったか？
Seimei-san!
(新八)晴明さん!!
What?!
Who are you?
(闇天丸)ｷｻﾏは!?
(銀時)ただのﾌｧﾝだ｡
Just a fan.
["That's How I Wish To Be,
Beautiful And Strong."]
うわ～！
ぐおっ！
Gin-chan!
(神楽)銀ちゃん！
It's still not enough!
まだまだ足りねえ!!
Give me more until it's
all hard and stiff!
もっと ﾋﾞﾝﾋﾞﾝに
かたくなるまでよこせ!!
What's this?!
あれは!?
They're channeling magic
into his blade...
木刀に呪をのせて…｡
うお～っ!!
That will have no effect on me!
そんなものが 我に効くか!!
うお～っ!!
Die!
死ね!!
You've got it wrong, Doman.
((違うぞ 道満｡
この法力はだな…｡
This should be...
You're amazing, Seimei-kun.
(道満)すごいや 晴明君｡
晴明君は ﾎﾞｸの知らない術➡
You know so many spells that I don't.
いっぱい 知ってるんだね))
体がいうことを…｡
Can't control the body...
うお～っ！
((大人たちは
ｹﾝｶばかりしてるけど➡
The grown-ups spend
all their time fighting,
ﾎﾞｸらなら きっと
仲よくやれるよね 晴明君｡
but I'm sure that we can
be friends, Seimei-kun!
ああ｡ 大きくなったら
ともに江戸を護るんじゃ｡
Yeah. When we grow up, we
will protect Edo together.
ﾜｼらが 手を組めば
最強じゃ 道満｡
We're unbeatable if we join forces, Doman.
It's a promise, Seimei-kun.
約束だよ 晴明君…｡
Yeah...
あぁ だから…
一緒に強くなろうな))
Let's get strong together, okay?
はぁっ！ てやっ！
この記憶は!?
What are these memories?!
It's too bad.
((残念じゃ お前とは
親友になれると思っていたのに))
I thought we could be friends.
These are... These are...!
これは… これは!?
I felt the same way...
((ﾎﾞｸだって… そうだよ))
Doman!
道満!!
うお～っ!!
Doman...
ど 道満…｡
Can it be? Are you...?
まさか お前… お前が
闇天丸の動きを封じて!?
Are you restraining Antenmaru?!
Seimei...
(道満)せ 晴明…｡
I refuse to listen to you...
誰が ｷｻﾏの言うことなど
聞くものか！
己の命ひとつで
すべてを終わりにする？
Sacrifice your life to end
this once and for all?
これ以上 ｷｻﾏに
いい格好させてなるものか｡
I refuse to let you have all the glory.
最後くらい
ｵﾚに格好つけさせろ！
Allow me this final moment.
道満様…｡
Lord Doman.
Quickly...
早く… ﾄﾄﾞﾒを｡ 今のうちに｡
Finish me off while you can...
うわっ ぐわっ！
I won't let that happen, Doman!
させぬぞ～ 道満！
ｷｻﾏごときが
我をおさえられるか！
A lesser being could never hold me back!
うお～！
Do it!
(道満)やれ～！
一千年のときを経て➡
The time has come for the
Ketsuno clan and Shirino clan
結野衆と巳厘野衆
一つになるときが来たのだ｡
to join together after a
thousand years of strife!
我ら破邪顕正の一族の力｡
Let us show him our clan's
might to vanquish evil!
とくと見せてやろうぞ！
Break free of our accursed fate!
呪われし因果の輪を打ち破れ！
Lord Doman!
(みんな)道満様！
That's...
あれは 銀さんの木刀に
みんなの力が集まっていく！
Their power is gathering
into Gin-san's blade!
Doman!
道満！
清明…｡
Seimei...
I've figured out how to make up with you.
仲直りの仕方 ｵﾚは わかったぞ｡
Protect Edo with me...
ともに 江戸を護ってくれ｡
うお～！
[ﾓﾆﾀ]ここ数日 降り続いた雨｡
We've had incessant rain
for the past few days,
それが 今朝がた未明
強風をともなう豪雨へと変わり➡
but early this morning, the wind picked
up and we now have a storm!
現在 江戸は
ご覧のような状況です｡
叩きつけられるような
激しい雨と風に➡
Battering rain and wind that make
it difficult to stand up straight!
立ってることすら
ままなりませ… ｷｬ～！
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)ｷﾞｬ～！ 戸が吹き飛んだ！
The door went flying!
Catherine-san, it's dangerous
to go outside.
(ﾀﾏ)ｷｬｻﾘﾝさん
外へ出るのは危険です｡
Tama!
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)ﾀﾏ～ お登勢さん ﾀﾏが！
Otose-san! Tama got...!
Look at this! The bridge has been
swept away by the torrent!
見てください 濁流に耐え切れず
橋が流されてしまいました｡
このままいけば
川の水が溢れかえり➡
At this rate,
it's only a matter of time before
the rain floods the entire city!
江戸市中が濁流に
飲み込まれるのも時間の問題…！
現在 江戸上空を覆っている
厚い雲は➡
The heavy clouds above Edo are
a mysterious phenomena that cannot be
picked up by our weather satellites!
気象衛星などにも
映し出されていない➡
謎の暗雲との情報が
入っております｡
いったい あの雲は何なのか!?
What are those clouds?!
What's going to happen to Edo?!
いったい 江戸は
これから どうなってしま…！
Please, making such a big
fuss over a hurricane.
(お登勢)なんだい どいつも
こいつも台風くらいで情けない｡
Isn't it your job to report the weather?
天気を伝えるのが
ｱﾝﾀらの仕事だろう｡
These fools will only make people panic.
どいつもこいつも不安だけ
あおるようなﾔﾂばかりだよ｡
Otose-san, help!
もっと 根性のすわったﾔﾂは…｡
Isn't there a reporter with some nerve to...
Good morning.
(結野)おはようございます｡
うお～！
受け取ったぜ｡
I can feel your raw emotion...
ﾃﾒｴらの思い こんだけﾃﾞｶきゃ➡
Big enough to reach anyone anywhere...
どこにだって誰にだって➡
きっと届く｡
Guaranteed...
どんなにぶ厚い暗雲も➡
Strong enough to cut through
ぶち抜いてみせら～！
these smothering dark clouds!
ｼﾞｬﾏだ 道満 消えうせろ！
Stop interfering, Doman!
Begone!
Your clan has been
cursed by darkness!
闇に覆われし呪われた一族よ｡
You can never clear away these clouds!
ｷｻﾏらに
この雲を払うことはできぬ！
The Mikado are fated to suffer
an eternal rain of hatred!
永劫のときを
怨念の雨に打たれ続けるが➡
ｷｻﾏら御門の運命だ！
[ﾓﾆﾀ](結野)長らく雨模様が
続いておりますが➡
How is everybody doing after
the extended period of rain?
皆さん どうお過ごしでしょう？
Are you feeling down because
of the gloomy weather?
[ﾓﾆﾀ]天気に引きずられて
暗くなってませんか？
Lost your cheer?
元気なくしてませんか？
The skies above Edo may be rough at the
moment, but you don't need to worry.
現在 江戸の空は
ご覧のとおりの荒れ模様ですが➡
何も心配はいりません｡
[ﾓﾆﾀ]やまない雨はありません｡
Rain must eventually end.
[ﾓﾆﾀ]晴れない雲はありません｡
Clouds must eventually part.
[ﾓﾆﾀ]だから 元気を出して➡
So cheer up.
みんなで一緒に願いましょう｡
Let us all wish together.
きっと届く きっと晴れる｡
Our hopes will reach...
I just know it...
天気も みんなの心も｡
The sun will shine...
Along with our hearts.
は～！
Here we go!
いくぞ！
Namaste.
南無｡
Tomorrow will be sunny!
(みんな)明日 天気になぁれ！
♪♪～
(道満)
あぁ… ようやく思い出した｡
Ah, I finally remembered...
ずっと見たかった…｡
What I always wanted
to see, to possess...
ずっと 手に入れたかった…｡
でも それは 手繰り寄せれば
手繰り寄せるほどに➡
But it would fade when
I tried to draw it close...
見えなくなる…｡
ｵﾚの隣ではない｡
Never meant to be by my side...
Now here is the forecast for today.
それでは
今日の天気 お伝えします！
今日の天気は➡
Today's weather is...
Sunny!
晴れで～す！
(道満)太陽…｡
It can only be seen when
standing in the sunlight...
その隣にあって
初めて見えるものであった…｡
あぁ…｡
Ah...
あの時と… なんら変わらぬ➡
Still the same as back then.
いい笑顔だ…｡
What a great smile...
♪♪～
すごい！
銀さんの…ﾀﾏを治している間に➡
Wow, they've almost rebuilt the place while
Gin-san was healing his xxxxicles.
屋敷も こんなに！
A considerable job for both
Onmyoji and shikigami.
(晴明)術者 式神 総出の
大仕事じゃ｡
Nobody will be able to return to protecting
Edo for the time being.
しばらくは皆 江戸守護の
任に戻れそうにないのう｡
えっ？ じゃあ おかみから
お咎めはなかったんですね？
Oh, then the Bakufu didn't
get mad at you?
江戸中に配した式神を
勝手に解いたのが➡
Someone mentioned how you'd get in trouble
for recalling the shikigami around Edo.
まずいとか言ってたけど…｡
事が事じゃ｡
The situation was dire.
あのまま 闇天丸を放っておけば➡
If we hadn't dealt with Antenmaru,
Edo would have been destroyed.
江戸は 壊滅していたからの｡
So you weren't fired.
That's good news.
ｸﾋﾞは つながったみたいｱﾙな！
よかった よかった！
えっ？ でも それじゃあ➡
But what about the Shirino clan, the
ones who summoned Antenmaru?
その闇天丸を呼び出した
巳厘野衆は 何か処断を？
Will they be punished?
Punished?
処断？ なぜ そのようなものが
必要なのじゃ？
Why would that be necessary?
闇天丸復活は 誰のせいでもない｡
Nobody can be blamed
for Antenmaru's revival.
一千年を経て
封印が弱まったことが原因じゃ｡
The seal on him had weakened
after a thousand years.
The Ketsuno clan and Shirino
clan cooperated to exorcise it.
そして
これを 結野衆と巳厘野衆➡
共に 力を合わせて調伏した｡
違うか？
Am I wrong?
晴明さん…｡
ﾌﾝ！
Seimei-san...
誰かさんが 大暴れしたせいで
屋敷だけじゃない｡
Thanks to a certain someone going on a
rampage, he not only wrecked our homes,
結野と巳厘野を 一千年に亘って
隔てていた大きな壁も➡
but utterly destroyed the huge wall that separated
the Ketsuno and Shirino for a thousand years.
跡形もなく
ぶっ飛んでしまったわ｡
まったく
どう責任をとってくれる？
Honestly, how is he going to take
responsibility for his actions?
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙを娶り
家督を継ぐだけでは足りぬぞ｡
Marrying Christel and taking over the family
won't be anywhere near enough.
ﾊﾊﾊ！ そりゃ銀さん 喜びますよ！
Gin-san would love to hear that.
(神楽)おい！ また 政略結婚で
悲劇を繰り返すつもりｱﾙか？
Hey, you gonna force her into another political
marriage and repeat the whole tragic mess?
何の得もないｱﾙよ
あんな甲斐性なし！
That sponge is worthless.
ﾌﾝ 冗談じゃ｡
I was only joking.
But I believe he will return
home for the time being.
だが
しばらくは 家に帰れると思うな｡
一族あげての盛大な酒宴が
待っておるぞ｡
The entire clan will be holding
a feast in his honor.
ところでﾔﾂは どこへ行った？
Speaking of which, where is he?
まだ…ﾀﾏが 治らんのか？
His xxxxicles haven't been healed yet?
お～い！
Hey!
一族あげての酒宴か…｡
The entire clan holding a feast...
I wish we had a chance to
share a glass with him.
どうせなら
ｱｲﾂも一緒に飲みたかったｱﾙ｡
ｱｲﾂにも
この空を 見せてやりたかったｱﾙ｡
I wish we could have showed
him this sky.
ほぉ…｡
Oh?
And who might you be talking about?
ｱｲﾂとはいったい 誰のことだ？
(２人)あぁっ!?
Where are you going?
(外道丸)
どこへ行くでござんすか？
主役がいないんじゃ
酒宴も開けないでござんす｡
We can't hold a feast without
the guest of honor.
Guest of honor?
主役？ ｱﾎか｡
ただのﾌｧﾝっつったろ！
Are you stupid?
I said that I'm just a fan.
それに
これ以上 ﾊﾞｶ騒ぎしちゃあ➡
And if I stick around, Ms. Ketsuno
will hear about what happened.
結野ｱﾅの耳に 入っちまうだろ｡
知られたくねえんだろ？
You don't want Ms. Ketsuno to find out
about this huge fight over her, do you?
結野ｱﾅのために
こんな騒ぎが 裏で起きてたこと｡
結野ｱﾅに知られないように
すべてを解決するため➡
You came with me so you could settle the
matter without her finding out, right?
ﾃﾒｴは ついてきたんだろ？
So you were planning to work for
free this entire time?
じゃあ 最初から
ﾀﾀﾞ働きするつもりで…｡
最初から ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様に 何も
伝わらないのを承知で こんな…｡
You knew that Lady Christel would never
learn of what happened, and still...?
Don't be ridiculous.
ふざけんな｡
誰が ﾀﾀﾞ働きなんかするか！
When have I ever worked for free?
Get this signed for me and send it back.
あとで これに
ｻｲﾝ書かせて送ってくれや｡
きっと 届けるでござんす｡
I promise to send it back.
この命に代えても➡
I'll get her to sign it "Gintoki Love,"
if it costs me my life.
銀時LOVE って
書かせてみせるでござんす｡
あんがとよ｡
銀時様…｡
Thanks a bunch.
Master Gintoki.
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様に
知られることがなくても➡
Lady Christel may never
know what happened,
あっしは 知ってるでござんす｡
but I will.
あっしは
決して忘れないでござんす｡
I will never forget what you did.
ずっと覚えてるでござんす｡
I will always remember my
other, precious master.
あっしの大切な
もう一人のあるじを…｡
どうか ご達者で｡
Please take care.
ん？
What is this...?
ｺｲﾂは…｡
ﾊｯﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
外道丸よ さすがは 結野の飼い犬｡
Gedomaru, I would expect no
less from a Ketsuno dog.
よく しつけが行き届いている｡
You have been trained well.
恩人を手ぶらで帰すが
結野のやり方か！
Do the Ketsuno make a practice of allowing
your savior to leave empty-handed?
どっ 道満！
Doman!
ﾊｯﾊｯﾊﾊﾊ！
なんで ﾃﾒｴが生きてんだ？
Why are you alive?!
ﾃﾒｴは！
You're...
Didn't you say that everybody's
wishes would get through?
きっと届くって
言ったじゃないすか｡
みんなの思いが届いたｱﾙ｡
They got through.
みんなの思いが… 道満さんを
助けたいという思いが➡
The desire everybody had to save
Doman-san drove away the darkness.
彼から闇を吹き払ったんです｡
The Shirino make a habit
of paying back favors.
借りた借りは返すが
巳厘野のやり方だ｡
者ども ﾔﾂらを
盛大に見送ってやれ！
Men, we shall see them off properly!
礼儀知らずの結野との違いを➡
Behold the difference between us and
the ill-mannered Ketsuno clan!
思い知らせてや…｡
道満様～!!
Lord Doman!
くぅ～…｡
(晴明)ﾊﾊﾊ！ 無様じゃな 道満！
Pitiful, Doman!
That's what you get for pushing yourself
too hard when you're still recovering!
病み上がりで ﾑﾘをするから
そんなことになるんじゃ｡
見よ！ 結野の華麗なる見送りを！
Watch as the Ketsuno give
them a majestic send-off!
ｷｻﾏら 下賤の者どもとの違いを
思い知れ！
Behold the difference between
us and the crude Shirino clan!
Seimei! Curse you!
(道満)晴明 おのれ！
ｷｻﾏには負けぬぞ！
You shall not defeat me!
見よ！
超絶華麗なる ｵﾚの美技を！
Observe my elegant and
beautiful technique!
(晴明)片腹痛いわ 道満！
Laughable, Doman!
見よ！
超絶ｽｰﾊﾟｰ 華麗なる ﾜｼの美技を！
Observe my super elegant
and beautiful technique!
超絶ｽｰﾊﾟｰﾊｲﾊﾟｰ 華麗なる美技！
Super hyper elegant and
beautiful technique!
超絶ｽｰﾊﾟｰﾊｲﾊﾟｰ ﾜﾝﾀﾞﾌﾙ
華麗なる美技！
Super hyper wonderful elegant
and beautiful technique!
超絶ｽｰﾊﾟｰﾊｲﾊﾟｰ ﾜﾝﾀﾞﾌﾙ ｴｸｾﾚﾝﾄ
華麗なる美技!!
Super hyper wonderful excellent
elegant and beautiful technique!
超絶ｽｰﾊﾟｰﾊｲﾊﾟｰ ﾜﾝﾀﾞﾌﾙ
ｴｸｾﾚﾝﾄ ﾀﾞｲﾅﾏｲﾄ 華麗なる美技!!
Super hyper wonderful excellent dynamite
elegant and beautiful technique!
超絶ｽｰﾊﾟｰﾊｲﾊﾟｰ ﾜﾝﾀﾞﾌﾙ ｴｸｾﾚﾝﾄ…｡
おい… ｱｲﾂら あれ➡
Super hyper wonderful excellent dynamite
ultimate elegant and beautiful technique!
Hey, look at them.
ﾎﾝﾄに仲直りできたのか？
Did they really make up with each other?
さぁ？ でも あの人たちは➡
Beats me.
But that's probably how
they're meant to be.
きっと あれでいいんですよ｡
行こう！ 銀ちゃん！
Let's go, Gin-chan.
きれいな百鬼夜行ｱﾙ｡
Such a pretty line of ghosts and demons.
Sounds like they're having
a lot of fun outside.
なんか楽しそうで いいね｡ 外は｡
ＤＶＤに録っとけって
残されちゃった｡
I'm stuck here recording this on DVD.
あ～ お宅も？ ｳﾁも大将が…
やってらんないよね｡
Oh, you too?
My boss ordered me to do the same.
It's such a drag...
(草野)それでは
完全復活を果たし➡
And now that her program's been brought
back, we have Ms. Ketsuno's horoscope.
番組続投が決まった
結野ｱﾅの星座占いです｡
ﾊｰｲ
今日 いちばんﾂｲている方は➡
Yes, the horoscope with
the most luck today
[Christel Ketsuno's Black Horoscopes]
天秤座の あなたです｡
is Libra.
特に 天秤座で ﾓｼﾞｬﾓｼﾞｬ頭｡
Especially if you're a Libra with bushy
hair and eyes like a dead fish...
死んだ…
魚のような目をしている方｡
(草野)あれ？
どうしたんですか？ 結野ｱﾅ｡
Huh? What's wrong, Ms. Ketsuno?
え… 泣いてる？
泣いてるんですか？
Huh? You're crying? Are you crying?
(結野)あなたの思いは きっと➡
I'm sure that your feelings
have reached everyone.
みんなに伝わっていますよ｡
だから 私にも
ひと言 言わせてください｡
So allow me to say this.
雨宿り侍さん ありがとう｡
To the samurai who was taking
shelter from the rain...
Thank you.
There you go.
てな わけだけどさ｡
だいたい何だよ ｢新訳｣って｡
Anyway, what's with the
"New Interpretation" crap?
We're going to pretend the story
on TV never happened?
前 ﾃﾚﾋﾞでやったのは
なかったことにすんの？
Or what?
それとも あれ？
前との違いが気になる方は➡
If you want to know how it was different
from the first go, buy the DVDs?
ＤＶＤなり買って見返せってか？
そうだよな｡
Yeah, or else it'll be all icky like trying to
find the differences without any answer.
そうしねえと答え合わせのない
間違い探しみたいで➡
気持悪いもんな｡
か～っ 汚ねえな 大人は｡
Man, grown-ups are so dirty.
なぁ 新八君｡
Don't you agree, Shinpachi-kun?
Could the main character not deny
the whole point of the movie?
いや 主人公が映画を
根底から否定するようなこと➡
今さら 言わないでください｡
私 もう いやｱﾙ｡
I can't take this anymore...
I can't bear to star in a film that's produced
by such dirty grown-ups...
こんな大人たちの作った映画の
主演なんてしたくないね｡
神楽ちゃん 主演じゃないよね｡
Kagura-chan, you're not
starring in anything.
まぁ そんなわけで今回は➡
Well, we're going to make it so you don't
have to refer back to the TV version
いちいち ﾃﾚﾋﾞ版を
見返さないでいいように➡
by recapping the Benizakura arc.
｢紅桜篇｣をおさらいしようと思う｡
いや… もう
そんなに尺 残ってないですよ｡
We don't have that much time left, you know.
Don't worry.
大丈夫だ｡ ｵﾚたち
事件の当事者なわけだし➡
We were there when it happened,
so we can summarize the
good parts in a digest.
いいとこだけ かいつまんで
ﾀﾞｲｼﾞｪｽﾄ版をお送りしよう｡
[Digest of Benizakura Arc]
こんな感じで｡
Like this!
消えた妖刀 紅桜｡
The disappearance of the demonic
sword, Benizakura.
消えた桂を追う
ｵﾚたち 万事屋は➡
[Might be too late...]
We members of Odd Jobs search
for the missing Katsura
[Gwah!!]
to find that Takasugi is plotting to
use Benizakura to destroy Edo.
一連の事件の背景に 紅桜を使い➡
江戸を壊滅させようと企む
高杉の存在があることを知る｡
Odd Jobs battles him to
stop his nefarious plot.
ﾔﾂの計画を阻止せんと
巨悪に戦いを挑む万事屋｡
次々と倒れていく仲間たち｡
次々と振り込まれる保険金｡
Comrades fall, one after another.
Insurance money comes in,
one check after another.
Gushing faster than the
eye can perceive!
ほとばしる目にもとまらぬ早技｡
うなる電光石火の目押し｡
Punching away at
lightning speed!
そんな激しい戦いの中で➡
As the fierce battle continues,
ｵﾚの中に眠っていたｱｲﾂが
ついに目を覚ます｡
a slumbering monster
within me awakens!
その名も… ｷｭｰﾃｨｸﾙ侍！
Its name is the Cuticle Samurai!
The hell are you twisting the facts for?!
って何 勝手に事実
ねじ曲げてんだ！
Your head's the twisted mess!
ｵﾒｴの頭は
ねじ曲がったまんまだっつうの！
ｳｿをつくな ｳｿを！ なに給料も
ﾛｸに払ってねえくせに➡
Stop telling lies!
You barely pay our salaries, but you bothered
to put us under accidental insurance?!
傷害保険だけ
ちゃっかり かけてんだ！
And you go off using the money to gamble?!
しかも ﾎﾞｸらの保険金で
ｽﾛｯﾄしてんじゃねえか!!
Pretty sure that was how it went...
たしか こんな話じゃ… あっ
ごめん｡ 生命保険だったかな｡
Oh, sorry.
They were life insurance policies...
余計ﾀﾁ悪いわ！
こんな話 映画になるかっ!!
That's even worse!
How could anyone make
a film out of this?!
You can't blame him for forgetting
stuff that happened in the past.
昔のことだから
ところどころ忘れてても
ﾑﾘないｱﾙ｡
私に任せるね｡
Let me handle this.
I remember Benizakura like
it happened yesterday.
｢紅桜｣のことなら
昨日のことのように覚えてるｱﾙ｡
[DIGEST OF BENIZAKURA ARC]
こんな感じだったよ｡
It was something like this.
消えた妖刀 紅桜｡
The disappearance of the demonic
sword, Benizakura.
I search for the missing Katsura,
消えた桂を追っていた私は
３日後 小田原市内で➡
and three days later in Odawara City,
I find Katsura without his memories
and with a unibrow.
記憶喪失状態の
眉毛のつながった桂を発見｡
話を聞くと 宇宙人にさらわれた
などと わけのわからん証言を…｡
Upon asking, he starts babbling
about being abducted by aliens.
最初から違うだろ！
それ ｢紅桜篇｣じゃねえだろ!!
You've got it completely wrong!
That has nothing to do with
the Benizakura Arc!
[Reference to the Noriko Sakai drug scandal.]
That's just the Tatsuya Gashuin mess!
ただの 我修院変じゃねえか！
そうだっけ？
Really? I have trouble remembering
what happened in the past.
昔のことだから
よく覚えてないｱﾙ｡
The one you described is ancient history!
そっちの事件のほうが
はるかに昔だわ!!
Don't confuse this with something
that happened twenty years ago!
何十年前の話と混ざってんだ！
Why did Zura go missing anyway?
そもそも ﾂﾞﾗって
なんで失踪したんだっけ？
Did he even go missing?
つうか 失踪なんかした？
皆目 覚えてねえじゃねえか！
You don't remember a single detail!
I'm not exactly sure, but Zura
was acting weird then.
よく わかんねえけど あの頃
ﾂﾞﾗは様子がおかしかったからな｡
急にﾗｯﾌﾟをしだしたり
髪振り乱して ＤＪやったり｡
He'd suddenly start rapping,
mess up his hair, and DJ.
で 戻ってきたら
髪が短くなってたんだっけ｡
And then his hair was shorter
when he came back.
Who the hell are you talking about?!
何の話だ！ そうじゃねえだろ！
That's not it!
The Benizakura Arc has
nothing to do with that!
｢紅桜篇｣は
そういう話じゃねえだろ!!
Oh, I see.
あ そっか｡ ｢紅桜篇｣っていうか
｢碧兎篇｣だったな これは｡
This was the Aoi Usagi Arc,
not the Benizakura Arc.
There's no such thing!
｢碧兎篇｣なんて ねえよ！
Who cares what color it is?
もう赤でも 碧でも
どっちでもいいｱﾙ｡
Though I'm totally against white.
白だけは ﾀﾞﾒｱﾙけどな｡
黙れ～!!
Shut up!
Just forget it!
もう いいから！
頼むから黙れ お前ら！
Could the two of you please shut up!
はっ しまった！
そうこうしているうちに➡
Oh, crap! We ran out of
time while arguing!
もう 尺がないぞ｡
仕方ないね｡
No choice. We'll use the fastest
and cheapest method!
いちばん手っ取り早くて
安くすむ方法で｡
そんなわけで
｢紅桜篇｣が気になる方は➡
So if you want to know
about the Benizakura Arc,
I recommend volumes 11
and 12 of the manga.
ｺﾐｯｸｽ 11巻12巻がｵｽｽﾒだ｡
映画を より深く楽しむために➡
A vital item for fully enjoying the movie.
欠かせないｱｲﾃﾑね｡
０巻の代わりに｡
In place of volume 0.
[Reference to the tenth One Piece film and its vol.0]
So this was all just
one big advertisement?!
って結局 これ
ただの宣伝じゃねえか!!
[Preview]
The next episode...
"Santa Claus Red is Blood Red!"
[Anyway, the theme song for the movie
is "Bakuchi Dancer" by DOES.]
[Bakuchi carries the dual meanings of
"advancing straight forward" and "gambling."]
[See you next time.]